Mom,would you relax?
妈，你放心好不好？
That was 10 blocks from here, and she was walking alone at night.
那里离这里有十条街 而且她是一个人在晚上走
I would never do that.
我绝不会那样的
Mom,come on,stop worrying.
妈，别担心了
This is a safe street. This is a safe building. There's nothing
这条街很安全，这栋楼很安全 没有任何东西…
Oh,my God! What are you doing in here?!
天啊！你跑进来干什么？
Mom,I gotta go! IT gotta go!
妈，我必须挂电话了！
Oh,my God!
天啊！
That's fine,you just read the paper.
没关系，你尽管看报
I'm gonna get a pot.
我要去拿个锅子
It's not for you.
不是为了你
Okay,that's fine.
好了，很好
Read the Family Circus...
看看漫画
...enjoy the gentle comedy....
享受一下幽默…
Oh,my God,my God,my God,my God....
喔，我的天，我的天 我的天…
It's open,you guys.
门是开的
Can I help you?
有何贵干？
Does Phoebe still live here?
菲比还住在这里吗？
No,she doesn't. But I can get a message to her.
没有，但我可以帮你传话
Great. Just tell her her husband stopped by.
好，告诉她 她老公来过这里
Her what?
她的什么？
How did you do that?
你怎么变出来的？
The One With Phoebe's Husband
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河马压缩制作 本字幕为河马根据R3DVD OCR得来
六人行 第2季 第04集 菲比的丈夫
This is unbelievable,Pheebs. How can you be married?
真是不可思议，菲比 你怎么会结婚？
I'm not "married" married,you know?
我不是“结婚”的结婚 你明白吗？
He's just a friend,and he's gay...
他只是个朋友 而且他是同性恋
...and he was from Canada, and he needed a Green Card.
而且他来自加拿大 他需要一张绿卡
I can't believe you married Duncan!
我不相信你嫁给了邓肯！
How could you not tell me? We told each other everything.
你怎么能不告诉我？ 我们什么事都告诉彼此
I'm sorry,but I knew if I told you, you'd get judgmental...
对不起，但如果我告诉你 你会批评我…
...and wouldn't approve.
不会赞成
Of course I wouldn't approve!
我当然不会赞成！
You were totally in love with this guy who,hello,was gay.
你爱死了那个同性恋
What the hell were you thinking?
你到底怎么想的？
See? And you thought she'd be judgmental.
瞧？我们还以为她很爱批评
I wasn't in love with him. I was helping out a friend.
我并不爱他 我只是帮助一个朋友
When he left town,you stayed in your pajamas for a month.
他离开后你一整个月都没下床
And I saw you eat a cheeseburger.
我还看到你吃乳酪汉堡
Well,didn't you?
有没有？
I might have.
也许有
I can't believe you didn't tell me.
我真不相信你没告诉我
Like you tell me everything?
你会告诉我一切事情吗？
What have I not told you?
我有什么没告诉你？
I don't know.
我不知道
The fact that the underwear out on the telephone pole is yours...
譬如说外面电线杆上的内衣…
...from when you had sex with Bobby on the terrace!
是你跟鲍比 在阳台上做爱时丢下去的！
What?
什么？
Wait a minute! Who told you?
谁告诉你的？
You are dead meat.
你死定了
I didn't know it was a big secret.
我不知道那是个大秘密
Oh,it's not big. Not at all.
不是大秘密 一点也不是
IKind of the same as,say...
比方说就像…
... I don't know,having a third nipple!
长了三个乳头！
You have a third nipple?
你有三个乳头？
You bitch!
你这贱人！
Whip it out! Whip it out!
秀一秀！秀一秀！
There's nothing to see! It's a tiny bump. It's totally useless.
没什么好看的！ 只是个小突起，没有用处
As opposed to your other multi-functional nipples?
你其他乳头有多种用途罗？
I can't believe you! You told me it was a nubbin.
我真不能信任你！ 你说那是个小包
Joey,what did you think a nubbin was?
乔伊，你以为小包是什么？
You see something,you hear a word, I thought that's what it was.
听到了一个名字 就不会多想了
-Let me see it again! -Yes,show us your nubbin!
让我再看一看！ 对，让我们看你的小包！
Joey was in a porno movie!
乔伊拍过色情电影！
If I'm going down, I'm taking everybody with me!
如果我要垮台 每个人都要跟我一起垮！
-Oh,my God! -You were in a porno?!
老天！ 你拍过春宫！
I was young and I just wanted a job.
当时我很年轻，只想找个工作
But I couldn't go through with it.
但最后一刻我无法做下去
They let me be the guy who fixes the copier but can't...
他们就让我演修影印机的人…
...because there's people having sex on it.
但是因为有人在上面做爱 所以无法修理
That is wild!
真是狂野！
-What's it shaped like? -ls it hairy?
形状是什么样子？ 有没有长毛？
What happens if you flick it?
碰到了会怎么样？
So does it do anything, you know,special?
有没有什么特殊功能？
Pressing my third nipple opens the delivery entrance...
只要压我的第三个乳头…
...to the magical land of Narnia.
就会开启了仙境之门
In some cultures,having a third nipple is actually a sign of virility.
在有些文化中 第三个乳头象徵了男性雄风
You get the best huts, and women dance naked around you.
有最好的住所 女人绕着你跳脱衣舞
Are any of these cultures, per chance,in the Tri-State area?
这些文化 是否可能在美国中部？
You know,you are so amazing. Is there anything you don't know?
你真是博学多闻 有什么是你不知道的？
Julie's so smart! Julie's so special!
茱莉好聪明！茱莉好特别！
I wanted you to hook up with Ross as much as you did.
我也希望你能与罗斯复合
But he's with her now. You'll have to get over it.
但现在他与她在一起 你必须忘了他
Oh,I'm going to have to get over it.
原来我必须忘了他
I didn't know that's what I had to do. I just have to get over it.
我不知道该怎么办 原来只要忘了他就好
-Sassy lady! -Where are you going?
性感美女！ 你要干什么？
I'm meeting Duncan. He's skating tonight at the Garden.
我要去见邓肯 今晚他要溜冰
He's in the Capades.
他参加了冰上剧团
-The lce Capades? -No,the Gravel Capades.
在冰上表演？ 不，在柏油路上表演
The turns aren't as fast, but when Snoopy falls? Funny.
转得不会很快 史努比跌倒时非常好笑
I can't believe you'd dress up for him.
我不相信你竟然为他打扮
You're setting yourself up all over again.
你又要重蹈覆辙了
Okay,no.
好的，不是
For your information,I'm seeing him so I can put those feelings behind me.
我去看他 就是为了能彻底忘了他
The reason I'm dressed like this is because I think it's nice...
我这样打扮是因为…
...to look nice for your gay husband.
我要让我的同性恋丈夫有面子
Darn it,we're all out of milk.
该死，没牛奶了
Chandler,will you fill me up here?
钱德，能不能给我一点？
I see,I see. Because of the third-nipple thing.
我懂了，因为第三个乳头？
Okay,sweetie,I'll see you later.
甜心，待会见
-See you later,Rach. -Bye-bye,Julie.
待会见，瑞秋 再见，茱莉
Come on,cut it out!
别闹了！
-Can I ask you something? -Sure.
我能问你一件事吗？ 好啊
What?
什么？
Come on,talk to me.
对我说吧
What's the longest you've been in a relationship before...
你与男人交往花了最久时间…
... having the sex?
才发生关系的是多久？
Why? Who's not? Are you and Julie not?
什么？谁没有…？ 你与茱莉还没有…
Are you and Julie not having sex?
你与茱莉还没有发生关系？
Technically?
技术上来说？
No.
没有
Is it because she's so cold in bed?
是不是因为她很冷感？
Or because she's kind of bossy, makes it feel like school?
或者她非常挑剔 感觉像是在学校？
No! She's great. And it's not like we haven't done anything.
不！她很好 我们又不是什么都没做
We do plenty of other stuff. Lots of other stuff like
我们做了很多事情 像是…
No! Don't need to know the details.
不！别告诉我细节
No,it's just....
不，只是…
It's me.
我的问题
I've only been with one woman my whole life...
我一辈子只跟一个人上过床…
...and she turned out to be a lesbian.
后来她变成了同性恋
So now I've got myself all psyched out.
所以现在我很担心
It's become,like,this...
就像是…
...this thing!
这件事！
You must just think I'm weird.
你一定以为我很怪
No,I don't think it's weird.
不，我不认为很怪
I think,in fact....
我想…
-ln fact,you know what I think? -What?
你知道我怎么想吗？ 怎么想？
I think it's sexy.
我觉得这很性感
Sexy?
性感？
Let me tell you something. As a woman...
让我告诉你，身为女人…
...there is nothing sexier...
没有任何事情…
...than a man who does not want to have sex.
比不想要作爱的男人更性感
No kidding?
真的？
You know what I'd do?
你知道我会怎么做？
I'd wait.
我会等待下去
-You'd wait? -Absolutely. I would wait...
你会等待？ 没错，我会等待…
...and wait....
一直等待…
Then I'd wait some more.
然后我还会再等下去
Really?
真的？
I don't care if she tells you she wants it,she begs,she pleads...
我不管她怎么说 她多么想要，多么恳求你…
...she tells you she's gonna have sex with another man
她说她要跟其他男人做爱…
That just means it's working.
这只表示收到了效果
Women really want this?
女人真的希望如此？
More than jewelry.
比珠宝还要渴望
Look at you! You look great!
你看起来真美丽！
Do l? Thank you.
真的？谢谢
So do you. Sparkly!
你也是，闪闪发亮！
This is pretty wonderful, Mr. Major Capades Guy!
真是很棒，剧团的主角
I remember when you were just King Friday in Mr. Roger's Ice Is Nice.
我还记得你只是 儿童节目上的道具
You always said I'd make it.
你一直说我会成功的
Well,you know, I'm kind of spooky that way.
我总是有这方面的怪才能
Gosh,I missed you!
啊，我想念你！
-I'm gonna get changed. -Okay.
我要换衣服 好的
Now.
现在就要
Oh! Right. Okay.
喔！对，好的
Ole!
冲刺！
What?
什么？
The Matador....
斗牛士…
Ole!
冲刺！
Sweetie,can you hold this for a second?
甜心，你能不能拿一下？
Sorry,you had a paleontologist on your face.
对不起，你脸上有个考古学家
But it's gone now. You're all right.
但现在没有了，没事
Hi,everyone.
嗨，各位
I wanted to thank you for our little talk before.
我要谢谢你先前的指点
No problem! So you're gonna go with the waiting thing?
没问题！所以你要等下去？
I was going to,but after I talked to you,I talked to Joey.
我本来要等 但是后来我又跟乔伊谈了
Good. What did he say?
很好，他怎么说？
He told me to get over myself and just do it.
他要我去做了就对
I thought about what you said and about what he said.
我衡量了你说的与他说的
And his way,I get to have sex tonight,so....
照他的话，今晚我就能做爱
What is this in my pocket?
我口袋里有什么东西？
Why,it's Joey's porno movie!
什么，是乔伊的春宫电影！
Pop it in!
放出来看看！
I'm fine,if you're okay watching a video...
我不介意 只要你们愿意看…
...filled with two-nippled people.
一大堆两个乳头的人
People having sex. That's just what I need to see.
大家都在做爱 正是我想要看的
What's wrong with people having sex?
做爱有什么不对？
Well,you know,these movies are offensive...
这些电影很冒犯人…
...and degrading to women and females....
侮辱女人与女性…
And the lighting's always unflattering.
灯光总是很呆板
-Monica,help me out here. -Hell,I wanna see Joey!
摩妮卡，帮我一下 管你的，我要看乔伊！
So is there a story? Or do they just start doing it right
有没有故事？ 还是立刻就开始…
Oh. Never mind.
别理会我
Wait a minute. That is the craziest typing test I've ever seen.
等一下 那是我见过最疯狂的打字测验
All I say is,she'd better get the job.
我只能说，她最好被聘用
Looks to me like he's the one getting the job.
看来是他被“聘用”了
Here I come.
我上场了
See,I'm coming to fix the copier.
我要修理影印机
I can't get to the copier. I'm thinking,"What do I do?"
但是我修不了 我在想：怎么办？
So I just watch them have sex.
所以我只好看他们做爱
Then I say Here's my line!
然后我要开口了！
You know,that's bad for the paper tray.
这对送纸匣很不好
Nice work,my friend!
干得好，老兄！
Wait,you see me again. Hang on, the guy's butt's blocking me.
等一下，又有我的镜头了 这砘锲ü傻沧∥伊
There I am. There I am. There I am....
我冒出来了，又来了 又来了，又来了…
So what's up? You came to see me yesterday.
怎么回事？ 昨天你来找我
I kind of need a divorce.
我需要跟你离婚
O...
喔…
... kay.
How come?
为什么？
Actually,I'm getting married again.
其实我又要结婚了
What?
什么？
I don't know how to tell you this.
我不知道要怎么说
I'm straight.
我不是同性恋
I don't understand. How can you be straight?
我不懂你怎么会是异性恋？
You're so smart and funny...
你又聪明又幽默…
...and you throw such great Academy Award parties!
而且举办很棒的奥斯卡派对！
That's what I kept telling myself.
我也一直这么告诉自己
But you reach a point where you can't live a lie anymore.
但是到了某个程度 就无法再扯谎下去了
How long have you known?
你知道了多久？
I guess on some level I always knew I was straight.
我想我一直知道 自己不是同性恋
I thought I was supposed to be something else.
我以为自己不是
I'm an ice dancer,all my friends are gay. I was just trying to fit in.
我是个冰上舞蹈者 所有朋友都是同志，我要合群
And there's actually a woman?
真的要跟一个女人结婚？
Her name's Debra.
她叫黛博拉
Well,is she the first that you've been with?
她是不是你的第一个女人？
I've never told you this...
我从来没告诉过你…
... but there were one or two times back in college when...
但在大学有一两次…
... I'd get drunk, go to a straight bar...
我喝得大醉，去了单身酒吧
...and wake up with a woman next to me.
醒来时身旁有个女人
I told myself it was the liquor, and everyone experiments in college.
我以为这是因为喝酒 而且大学每个人都在摸索
Sure.
当然
Now I know I don't have a choice. I was born this way!
现在我知道我没有选择 我生下来就是如此！
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
You're married to someone for six years and you think you know him.
嫁给一个人六年 以为自己很了解他
And then one day he says, "Oh,I'm not gay!"
结果一天他说： 我不是同性恋！
I'm still me.
我还是我
Why couldn't you just have figured this out six years ago?
你为什么在六年前 没有发现这件事？
You know,it still smells like monkey in there.
里面闻起来还是有猴骚味 （罗斯养过猴子）
That saves us the conversation.
我们又有话可聊了
This has been great, but I'm officially wiped.
今晚很好玩，但我累死了
Me too. We should get going.
我也是，我们该走了
No! Come on,you guys!
不！你们别这样！
Come on,it's only 1 1 :30.
现在才十一点半
Let's just talk. We never just hang out and talk anymore.
让我们好好聊聊 我们最近都没有一起聊过天
Rachel,that's all we do.
瑞秋，我们在一起只有聊天
Maybe that's all we do. What about Julie?
也许我们是如此 但是茱莉呢？
What about Julie?
茱莉怎么样？
You have been in our lives for nearly two months now...
你已经加入我们将近两个月了
...and we don't really know you.
我们还没有真正认识你
I mean,who is Julie?
茱莉究竟是什么样的人？
What do you like? What don't you like?
你喜欢什么？不喜欢什么？
We want to know everything.
我们什么都要知道
Well,that could take awhile.
这可能要花一段时间
So?
所以呢？
Who here does not have the time to get to know Julie?
谁没有时间更认识茱莉？
I got the time to get to know Julie.
我有时间来认识茱莉
I know her pretty well. Can I go?
我跟她很熟了 我能回去吗？
That's fine.
没关系
Let's start with your childhood. What was that like?
让我们从你的童年开始 你的童年是怎么样？
In a nutshell
简单地说…
So,have you told your parents?
你告诉了你父母吗？
No,but it'll be okay. They're pretty cool.
还没有，应该没关系 他们都很酷
My brother's straight,so....
我弟弟是异性恋，所以…
Here you go.
就是这样了
You know what? I just have one more question.
我还有一个问题
If you had figured this out sooner, and I had been around...
如果你早一点知道 而我也在你身边…
...do you think l would have been the one...?
你想会不会是我…？
No. Don't tell me.
不，别告诉我
I don't think either answer would make me feel better. Here.
我想不管什么回答 都不会让我更好过
I love you,Phoebe.
我爱你，菲比
So your brother's straight,huh?
所以你弟弟是异性恋？
Seriously.
说真的
and my second-grade teacher was Miss Thomas...
我的二年级老师是汤玛丝小姐
...and my first-grade teacher was Mrs. Cobb.
我的一年级老师是柯布小姐
Mrs. Gobb?
葛布小姐？
No,Cobb. Like cobb salad.
不，柯布，就像柯布沙拉
What exactly is in a cobb salad?
柯布沙拉里面究竟有什么？
I'm going home.
我要回家了
Boy,that Julie's a talker,huh?
茱莉真是爱说话，嗯？
Good night.
晚安
It's pretty late. You're probably not still planning on....
很晚了，你们大概没有打算…
No,I am.
我有
Are you nervous?
你紧张吗？
I have done it before.
我以前做过
I mean,how are you gonna handle it?
你要如何进行？
Are you gonna talk about it beforehand? Are you just gonna pounce?
要先谈谈？还是就上了？
I don't know. I guess I'm just gonna...
我不知道，我想我要…
...see what happens.
顺其自然
Good luck!
祝你好运！
What?
什么？
Nothing....
没事…
It is your first time with her, and if the first time doesn't go well...
这是你与她的第一次 如果第一次就不顺利…
...well then,that's pretty darn hard to recover from.
那就很难再东山再起
Okay,now I'm nervous.
好，现在我紧张了
Maybe you should put it off.
也许你应该延期
No,I don't want to put it off!
不，我不要延期！
I spent last year being so unbelievably miserable.
我去年一整年都很悲惨
And now I'm actually happy.
现在我很快乐
You know,I mean really happy.
真的很快乐
I just don't wanna....
我不希望…
I don't wanna mess it up,you know?
我不希望搞砸了，你知道吧？
I know.
我知道
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's not your fault.
这又不是你的错
Right.
嗯…
Maybe it doesn't have to be this tough.
也许不需要这么困难
Maybe you were on the right track with that whole "spontaneous" thing.
也许你顺其自然是对的
-Women really like that. -Really?
女人真的喜欢这样 真的？
I mean if it were me, I'd want you to....
如果是我，我会希望你…
I don't know,catch me off guard with a really...
趁我没有防备的时候…
...good kiss.
好好给我一个吻
Really sort of soft at first.
刚开始要很轻柔
And then maybe brush the hair away from my face.
然后也许把我的头发拨开
And then look far into my eyes...
凝视我的眼睛…
...in a way that lets me know something...
让我知道有美妙的事情…
...amazing is about to happen.
快要发生了
And then,I don't know,then...
然后，我不知道，然后…
...you'd pull me really close to you so that...
你会更紧地搂住我…
...so that I'd be pressed up right against you.
我会紧紧帖着你…
And it would get kind of...
然后就会开始…
...sweaty...
流汗…
...and blurry.
目眩神迷…
And then it's just happening.
一切就自然发生…
Thanks,Rach. Good night!
谢谢，瑞秋，晚安！
Oh,God!
天啊！
Good morning!
早安！
Well,somebody got some last night!
昨晚有人爽到了！
Twice!
两次！